Vinício Oliveira

BIOINFORMATICS | SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Guimarães, Portugal

vinimig.github.io

vinicio.mpv.oliveira@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Versatile and curiosity driven Bioinformatician by education, with 4+ years of experience in Software Development for High Content Screening + 1.5 years as a Spotfire Consultant in the Pharma Industry. Currently deeply interested in the world of Artificial Intelligence and looking to earn my place in it.

KEYWORDS

Python, R, TIBCO Spotfire, Software Development, Data Visualization, Dashboards, Web Development (HTML, CSS, javascript, PHP, React), Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Life Sciences

EDUCATION —

Universidade do Minho

Braga, Portugal Master's degree in Bioinformatics, 2015

Universidade do Minho

Braga, Portugal BSc in Biochemistry, 2012

Erasmus student at Universitá degli studi di Milano Statale, Milan, Italy, 2012

Machine Learning by Stanford University & DeepLearning.Al on Coursera.

Certificate earned on November 5, 2023
https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/MGBXTKY3S76S

Deep Learning by DeepLearning.Al on Coursera.

Certificate earned on March 30, 2024

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/YFVXX53SHW4L

EXPERIENCE

July 2021 – October 2022

TIBCO Spotfire Consultant • BinarySeason (Portugal - Remote)

Development of interactive analysis dashboards with TIBCO Spotfire platform, for the pharma industry, mainly using IronPython, HTML and javascript. Additionally, some simple SQL queries for data retrieval. Gathered requirements and implemented a set of dashboards for the different stakeholder groups within the client company accordingly.

April 2020 – December 2020

Sr Software Development Engineer • PerkinElmer (Tres Cantos, Madrid)

Research and Development of analytical applications for High Content Screening and Drug Discovery with the TIBCO Spotfire API (C# and R). Frequently collaborated with QA team to perform BDD testing. Higher responsibility in the lifecycle of applications playing a wider role in the development of the same.

August 2016 - April 2020

Software Development Engineer • PerkinElmer (Tres Cantos, Madrid)

Coming from a 6-month internship in the company, integrated the R&D team for the implementation of R analytical methods for applications under the TIBCO Spotfire platform. Additionally proof of concept creation was performed using IronPython. Initial contributions using the C# API and regular participation in code reviews and contact with QA testing.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Native)

English (Proficient)

Spanish (Advanced)

Italian (Intermediate)